# Raphael Ofori Mensah

+233 543213064 | ralphmensah | 23@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/raphael-ofori-mensah | github.com/ralphmensah

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience and a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight its core competencies, and further their success.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, Python, Java, SQL(PostgresSQL), HTML/CSS

Frameworks: Angular, SpringBoot, Angular Material, Bootstrap 4

Developer Tools: Git/GitHub, Jira, VS Code, IntelliJ IDE

## **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer Accra, Ghana

Morgan Stanley

July 2021- Present

- Collaborated in a team of four Engineers to design and build user-friendly software interfaces using Angular 2 and Express JS to simplify the overall internal trading experience for traders.
- Wrote and tested Angular Widgets using the Karma and Jasmine Testing Frameworks and Jenkins for Continuous Integration/ Continuous Delivery(CI/CD) to render quality code and faster development time.

## **Software Engineer Associate**

Accra, Ghana

*Turntabl.io* 

Sep 2020- Present

- Worked on Morgan Stanley systems as a contingent employee to build scalable
- Wrote and tested Angular Widgets using the Karma and Jasmine Testing Frameworks and Jenkins for Continuous Integration/ Continuous Delivery(CI/CD) to render quality code and faster development time.

## **Software Internship Trainee**

Koforidua, Ghana

Global Code Summer Program

July 2019- July 2020

- Developed web applications using Flask(Python) and Jinja Templating Engine.
- Managed project repositories using Git and GitHub

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Koforidua Technical University**

Koforidua, Ghana

Computer Science, HND

Aug. 2017- July 2020

## **PROJECTS**

# <u>SheetLabs</u> | Springboot, Java, PostgresSQL, Angular

Feb.2021- July 2021

- collaborated with a team of four engineers to migrate a web app that helps users create restful APIs for exiting spreadsheets (xls/xlsx) while enforcing access restrictions from PHP and sqlLite to Java and PostgresSQL.
- also worked on payment integrations using the stripe API.

Green Ghana Day 11th June 2022

• With plants playing a significant role in our environment, On green Ghana day, I went out with a few of my colleagues into one of the most extensive forests in Ghana, the Achimota Forest to plant more trees(Mahogany, Militia). This is my way of helping create a sustainable environment.

# NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Good Team Player
- Good Communication Skills
- Efficient at googling and figuring things out

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Hacker Rank Angular Certified(Basic)